>> Now that we've covered some different way you can divert traffic,
我们谈过了不同的分流方式
how would you actually choose between them?
那你如何在它们之间做出选择呢？
>> So there are really three main considerations.
主要考虑有三点
The first was user consistency.
第一是用户一致性
If you're using a user ID, then the user gets a consistent experiences as they
如果使用用户 ID 那么用户获得的体验是连贯的
change devices as long as they're signed in.
只要是登录状态 就算更换设备也不会影响体验
And so for a certain set of changes, so for example,
那么对于某些更改 比如
if you're testing how courses are being displayed,
测试课程展示效果
then the user will get a consistent experience across devices.
那么用户在各个设备的体验都是一致的
Now, on the other hand, if you're testing a change that crosses the sign
另一方面 如果你测试的更改项会影响登录前后的效果
in, sign out border, then a user ID doesn't work as well.
那么用户 ID 用处就不大了
So for example, if you're changing the layout of the page or
比如 如果你要变更页面布局
the location of the sign in bar.
或登录按钮的位置
In that case, you may want to use a cookie instead, so you get consistency
此情况下 你反而会用 cookie 使登录前后体验一致
across the sign in and sign out border, but not across devices.
但不能保证设备间的一致
>> Okay.
好的
So then would you always want to use a user ID or a cookie if you can, so
所以 只要情况满足 你总会使用用户 ID 或 cookie
that you will get some type of consistency?
以获得某种一致性 对吗？
>> For user visible changes, you would definitely use a cookie or a user ID.
对于用户可见更改 你一定会使用 cookie 或 用户 ID
Now the thing is that,
现在问题是
there's probably a whole host of changes that are not visible to users.
可能许多更改都是用户看不见的
This can range from latency changes to backend infrastructure changes or
从延迟变化到后台架构的变化
honestly, ranking changes.
或说是排序变化
Most of the time, users can't tell when you change the ranking function.
很多时候 用户无法辨别排序功能的改变
Now, user visibility's one consideration as to whether you
用户可见性是考虑因素之一
want to use a user ID or cookie.
它决定使用用户 ID 还是 cookie
The other thing is what you want to measure.
另一个要考虑的是你的测量内容
So for example, if you want to measure a learning effect, whether or
比如 如果你想测量学习效果
not users adapt to change.
用户是否适应更改
In those cases,
在这些案例中
you also need a stateful unit of diversion like a cookie or user ID.
你还是需要 cookie 或用户 ID 这种状态稳定的分组单元
For example, if you're making a latency where, that you're making the site
比如 如果你在设置网络延迟 网站速度减缓
slower and you're trying to see whether or not the user uses the site less.
你要确认用户使用量是否减少
In those cases, you need to use a cookie or
这种情况下 你需要用 cookie 或用户 ID
a user ID to see what happens across time.
去检查一段时间内的情况
So even when the user doesn't notice the change,
即便用户注意不到变化
depending on what you want to measure, you may also choose a user ID or cookie.
但还得看你要测量的是什么 你可以选择用户 ID 或 cookie
>> Okay. That makes sense.
好的 很有道理
And how about IP based diversion, how does that compare?
那么相比之下 基于 IP 地址的分组怎么样？
>> So generally speaking, I don't find IP based diversion very useful.
一般上 我觉得基于 IP 地址的分组用处不大
You don't get the consistency that you get from a user ID or a cookie,
不像用户 ID 或 cookie 它不具备一致性
because the user's IP address could randomly change depending on what's
因为用户的 IP 地址会随机变化
happening with the provider nor
这取决于你的网络提供商
do you get the clean randomization that you get from like event based diversion.
IP 地址也无法提供如基于事件分组的随机结果
Now that said,
虽然这么说
there's a whole host of changes where IP based diversion may be your only choice.
可很多变更或许只能用基于 IP 的分组
So let's say, for example, your testing out an infrastructure change when you're
比如 你要测试架构的变化
testing out one hosting provider versus a different hosting provider to
你会在两个主机服务商之间作比较
understand the impact of latency.
从而了解网络延迟的影响
In that situation, IP based diversion may really be your only choice.
这种情况下 基于 IP 的分组会是唯一选择
Now when you're doing IP based diversion,
当你使用基于 IP 的分组
one of the key challenges is actually in the analysis.
一个关键的难点就在于分析
Because what happens with IP based diversion is that you
因为通过基于 IP 地址的分组 你无法
may not get a clean comparison between your experiment and your control.
在实验组和对照组之间获得纯粹的对比结果
One example of this is, for example, modem dialups.
一个例子就是 调制解调器拨号
I know it's not very common anymore, but it can still happen.
我知道它不太流行了 但还在使用
And what happens for some providers is they all aggregate all of those modem
一些供应商会集合这些调制解调器拨号用户
dialup users into a single IP address.
到一个 IP 地址下
And so then the question is how do I find that comparable population of users
那么问题是我怎么才能找到对照组内
in my control?
可比较的用户总体？
And so what you're going to do analytically,
所以 基于 IP 分组后要做的是
when you do IP based diversion is doing a lot of post analysis to try and
通过很多后续分析试着找到
find those good comparisons between your experiment and control.
实验组和对照组的对比